<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[integrating design]]></title>
  <link href="http://hilary.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://hilary.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-30T00:34:04-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://hilary.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[hilary j holz]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Delicious, Finally]]></title>
    <link href="http://hilary.github.com/blog/2012/:category/on-delicious/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-28T14:28:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://hilary.github.com/blog/2012/:category/on-delicious</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I joined <a href="http://www.delicious.com/">Delicious</a> (formerly styled del.icio.us) yesterday. For
those of you living under a rock for the past decade, Delicious is the
original social bookmarking web service.<!--more--></p>

<h2>problem</h2>

<h3>multiple browsers</h3>

<p>As a web geek, I run many browsers at once. A typical setup for me
would be:</p>

<ol>
<li><a href="http://www.mozilla.org/firefox">Firefox</a>, under my development profile (which I have captured in
<a href="http://www.macosxautomation.com/automator/">Automator</a> and imaginatively named <code>FF dev</code>). Three to four
windows open to various parts of the site I&#8217;m currently working on.</li>
<li>Firefox, under my personal profile (captured in Automator). A
dizzying set of windows and tabs open to reference material.</li>
<li>Firefox, under my Facebook profile (yup, you guessed it). I have a
major FB project going at present and check in regularly. On the
other hand I value my concentration, so I have it sandboxed.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.google.com/chrome/">Chrome</a>, because Google docs and especially Google spreadsheets
work best with chrome.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.apple.com/safari/">Safari</a>, because the <a href="http://safaribooksonline.com/">Safari Bookshelf</a> seems happiest with
Safari.</li>
</ol>


<p>Bookmarks local to a single browser simply don&#8217;t meet my needs.</p>

<h3>rich associations</h3>

<p>I have hundreds of bookmarks, the vast majority of which link to a
selected entry page for an information-rich web resource. Choosing a
single slot in a rigid hierarchy for each bookmark is frustrating and
counter-productive. With in-browser bookmarks, I frequently find it
easier to search for the resource with a few strategic terms than to
recall in which of several related categories I put a particular
resource.</p>

<p>Delicious pioneered using those terms (called <em>tags</em>) as the
organizing principle for a set of bookmarks. Entering any of a
bookmark&#8217;s tags will bring up that entry, along with any other
resources on which I have used the same tag. Tags not only eliminate
the frustration during bookmarking and ease retrieval, they facilitate
discovering new relations in the bookmarked materials.</p>

<p>While many browsers now support tagged bookmarks, that support is
limited to storing tags, leaving their use in retrieval to extensions.
Furthermore, tags really benefit from social support: a starter set
of suggested tags can make all the difference between creating a rich
set of personalized tags and not using the feature at all.</p>

<h3>sync, sank, sunk</h3>

<p>I&#8217;ve explored alternatives to in-browser bookmarks before. Several
years ago I researched the bookmark syncing services and even tried
Xmarks for a brief time. Xmarks syncing had a very noticeable impact
on my mac, however, so I dropped it. I will say that I was not a
particularly good fit for the syncing approach to bookmarks as I am
generally conservative when it comes to resources and syncing seems
like overkill to me.</p>

<h3>social, yes, promiscuous, no</h3>

<p>I have liked the idea of a social bookmarking site from the
beginning. Having said that, I do not necessarily want all my
bookmarks to be public. Two situations in which I would use private
bookmarks that immediately come to mind are sites I have not yet
visited in any depth but plan to explore later and sites that
serve as examples of what not to do.</p>

<p>Keeping two entirely separate sets of bookmarks: a public set in a
social bookmarking service and a private set of in-browser bookmarks
will inevitably reduce the richness of both sets, not to mention
increase my workload.</p>

<h2>solution</h2>

<p>Enter Octopress. I have just moved my blog to Octopress (for some
value of moved; I still need to process the posts on my old blog but
decided not to let that delay launching the new one). One of
Octopress&#8217;s default properties is that it integrates your Delicious
feed. How cool is that? Time to go revisit Delicious.</p>

<p>I explored Delicious shortly after it came out and again several years
later and decided not to use it. Both times the determining factor
was interaction design: the drag on my workflow was such that I was
confident it would get in the way of my productivity.</p>

<p>This time, however, I was pleasantly surprised. While it is early days
as of yet, I&#8217;m already integrating the beta bookmarklet into my
workflow. The interface is nice and clean, although even the &#8216;compact&#8217;
version takes up a huge amount of space. But that&#8217;s what user styles
are for&#8230;</p>

<p>I decided not to upload my bookmarks from my various browswers, but
rather to enter them as I came to them: I was due to sort through the
things anyway.</p>

<p>Thanks, Octopress. Not only do I have a blogging platform on which
I can actually write again, but it looks like I may have an answer
to my perennial bookmark problem!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
